Part of our sport requires that a rider know how to go in select the correct cow bring it out and get it singled all by itself.
Our rider happens to have an easy right there we have decided that we are going to get the number three cow with the horn's.
All she needs to know is what we had learned in our previous segment about how to put pressure on the cow and ask it to come on out.
By maneuvering our horse in between the cow and the heard and continuing to push on it.
We will have her turn around now and go in and try and get one that's just a little bit more difficult.
She will select a cow that makes her go into the heard in what we call you want to kind of slice it right down the middle.
Deciding which way do I want to send that cow.
I am going to try to hold the heard with just one person that might be a little bit difficult but my job is to keep that heard form wanting to go bust or getting out of the, of the boundaries we have set.
Cows want to return to where they came from so as she goes into get her cow she's trying to keep just the pressure on the one cow that she's after.
So if she was going after the black cow and she was able to successfully get it out.
We just didn't hold the heard as well as we would like to.
All of those skills about working a cow are what make this part just as successful as learning to track and control it.
We will go ahead and get one more cow and see if we can bring that one out.
When we go into get the cow we are thinking about the cow and you put pressure on your good cow.
Pressure is almost magical to me.
It means that the rider is just keep her eyes, her horse on one particular cow as the rest of them stay back in with the heard.
So we got that cow out pretty successfully just losing one in the process.
Most of the time we might have two or three what we call turn backs or heard settlers.
That make this just a little bit easier and organized.